Finding Aid for the Book Artifacts Collection, circa 2345 B.C.-1993 A.D. (bulk circa 1510-1976)
The Bancroft Library
- Typography, T8
  A set of French punches acquired through Dawson’s in Los Angeles has been traced to the Fonderie Pettibon in Paris and Joseph Vibert, who worked there under supervision of Pierre Didot. The style closely resembles that of the typeface of Didot’s 1799 edition of Horace.
  - Typesetting history, T82
    - Display Folder
    - Historical example: Gowdy address label, T82K4, No. 1
    - Historical examples: Portfolios and letterheads designed by Carl Puttington Rollins, T82K4, No. 2
    - Historical examples: Portfolios and letterheads designed by G.H. Perry, T82K4, No. 3
    - Historical examples: Portfolios and letterheads designed by H.G. McMennamin, T82K4, No. 4
  - Type Design, T83
    - Pattern making for matrix cutting by machine, T83, No. 1
  - Handcast type, T84
    - Clay-type, re-created, T84C6
    - Historical specimans: Korean moveable type, ca. 15th C., T84K7, No. 1-2
    - Molds: Caslon hand type mold, 18th C., T84M7, No. 1
    - Punches: Punch Cutting Display, T84P8, No. 1
    - Punches: Handcut punch, stepped for accent, T84P8, No. 2
    - Punches: Punched matrix for hand mold, T84P8, No. 3
    - Puches: Handcut counterpunch, T84P8, No. 4
    - Punches: Vibert-Didot punches, 19th C., T84P8, No. 5
    - Punches: Roger Levenson Collection, T84P8, No. 6
    - Modern Specimans: Teaching example handcast by Roger Levenson, T84T8, No. 1
    - Modern specimens: Type cast from Fell matrix of 1686, T84T8, No. 2
  - Typesetting by hand, T85
    - Type storage: cases: Type case, Chinese, T85B8
    - Type storage: cases: Bellows, T85B86, No. 1
  - Casting and setting by machine, T86
    The principles of casting type by machine are illustrated by two permanent displays, "Patterns, Punches, and Matrices," and "Matrices and Type," both mounted with explanatory text by Roger Levenson. Finished electrotyped foundry matrices of Mountjoye (Bell) roman and italic and of accents for the Oxford type used for the John Carter Brown Library Catalog, Bibliotheca Americana (Providence: The Library, 1919-31), came from Daniel Berkeley Bianchi. The proprietary type designed for the Merrymount Press by Herbert P. Horne is shown in a 14-point display given by Wilbur L. Doctor.
    A further Bianchi gift from the Merrymount Press is a very large collection of typecast ornaments: Caslon designs from Stephenson & Blake, examples from the Lanston Monotype Corporation, and from the American Type Founders Company, Naudin ornaments on Didot body, Bruce Pen Ornaments, Binny and Ronaldson ornaments, Norman Munder ornaments, proprietary printers flowers designed by Percy Smith of London exclusively for the Merrymount Press, and ornamental ships made from wood engravings (by an 18th century stereotyping process) at the Caslon foundry.
    A second large collection type ornaments, from the shop of John Henry Nash, contains an Italian series from Societa Nebiolo in Turin, Italy, and several long German series, including many two- and three-color designs, from the two defunct Leipzig foundries of Bauer, and Schelter & Giseke. This collection is housed in a cabinet of a style once used by foundries for the storage of sorts. It is also from the Nash shop.
    Since the latter part of the 19th century, type for fine commercial and book work has usually been cast and set mechanically on monotype machines, which produce lines of single types and spaces; for most work, especially newspapers, linotype machines cast single lines or slugs all in one piece. Assembled matrices and type from these machines may be contrasted with a slug from a Ludlow machine, which casts type after matrices have been set by hand.
    The chief example of forms composed on monotype and linotype machines is also a memento of both a printers' tour de force and United Nations Conference in San Francisco. As the meeting was drawing close in 1945, the University of California Printing Despartment and five San Francisco firms combined forces, under the direction of the Government Prinitng Office, to produce within a single week the multi-lingual first edition of The United Nations Charter (San Francisco: 1945). The Russian and Chinese forms preserved in The Bancroft Library are from the Printing Department of the University of California.
    Stereotyping, a 19th century process of casting whole pages in type metal from a matrix, or mold of plaster of Paris or papier-mâché, is illustrated by a flong for newspaper reproduction and by most of the plates for Robert Wolter's A Short and Truthful History of the Taking of California and Oregon by the Chinese in the Year A.D. 1899 (San Francisco: A.L. Bancroft, 1882)". They are the gift of Aylett Cotton. Half the plates are stored with contemporyary wedges in an original box. A form given by Robert Howell shows the method of mounting for reproduction.
    Throughout the collection there are numerous examples of printing surfaces prepared by the other important 19th and 20th century process, electrotyping, or the depositing of metal coating on a wax impression or in an electrotype mold.
    - Collections: Patterns, punches and matrices display, T86A1, No. 1
    - Collections: Matrices and type display, T86A1, No. 2
    - Collections: Forms example: United Nations Charter, 1945, T86A1, No. 3
    - Collections: Electrotype: University of California Old Style (Goudy), T86A1, No. 4
    - Collections: Merrymount Press Montallegro type matrices, T86A1, No. 5
    - Matrices: Accents and special characters, Oxford type, Merrymount Press (electrotyped), T86F61, No. 1
    - Matrices: Roman and italic, Mountjoye (Bell) type, Merrymount Press (electrotyped), T86F61, No. 2
    - Matrices: Japanes characters (electrotyped), T86F61, No. 3
    - Matrices: Japanese character (engraved), T86F61, No. 4
    - Molds: Body slide mold for automatic caster, T86F612, No. 1
    - Types: Type cast in a pivotal caster, T86F62, No. 1
    - Types: Typecast ligature, T86F62, No. 2
    - Types: Typecast spacing material, T86F62, No. 3
    - Exotic types: Chinese, T86F623 C22
    - Exotic Types: Japanese, T86F23 J24
    - Typecast ornaments, T86F627
    - Typecast ornaments: Crown Zellerbach Collection, T86F627 C4
    - Typecast ornaments: Ted Freedman Collection, T86F627 F82
    - Typecast ornaments: Hart Collection, T86F627 H37
    - Typecase ornaments: MacKellar, Smith and Jordan, T86F627 M36
    - Typecast ornaments: Mackenzie-Harris Collection, T86F627 M37
    - Typecast ornaments: The Merrymount Press Collection, T86F627 M38
    - Typecast ornaments: John Henry Nash Collection, T86F627 N27
    - Typecast ornaments: Frederick Folger Thomas Jr. Collection, T86F627 T5
    - Linotype: Assembled linotype matrices, T86L46, No. 1
    - Linotype: Linotype slugs, T86L46, No. 2-3
    - Linotype: Original machine drawings for linotype model 2, T86L46, No. 4
    - Ludlow type casting: Ludlow slug, T86L84, No. 1
    - Ludlow type casting: Engraved matrix, T86L84, No. 2-3
    - Monotype: Display folder, T86M66, No. 1
    - Monotype: Punch-cutting display, T86M66, No. 2
    - Monotype: Composed line: University of California Old Style, T86M66, No. 3
    - Monotype: Specimen alphabet: Univesity of California Old Style, T86M66, No. 4
    - Monotype: Matrices, various styles and sizes, for text composition, T86M66, No. 5
    - Monotype: Display types, various styles and sizes, for hand composition, T86M66, No. 6
    - Monotype: Electro-matrices, San Serif Bold, for display composition, T86M66, No. 7
    - Monotype: Engraved matrices, 72 pt. for display composition, T86M66, No. 8
    - Monotype: Engraved matrices, 14 pt., for display composition, T86M66, No. 9
    - Monotype: Rectangular matrix, 12pt. for text composition, T86M66, No. 10
    - Monotype: Bembo matrices, 12 pt. for text composition, T86M66, No. 11
    - Monotype, Computer-activated, T86M667
    - Stereotype: Plates for book: Wolter, Robert. A Short and Truthful History...San Francisco, A. L. Bancroft, 1882, T86S84, No. 1-2
    - Stereotype: Published copy of book cited above, T86S84, No. 3
    - Stereotype: Sample proofs for book cited above, T86S84, No. 4
    - Stereotype: Matrix: China Times, T86S84, No. 5
    - Stereotype: Stereotype Mounts, T86S84, No. 6
    - Stereotypes: Matrices for newspaper from pages, T86S84, No. 7-8
    - Electrotypes: United Nations Emblem, T86S85, No. 1
    - Electrotypes: Electrotype made from handset type, T86S85, No. 2
    - Flexographic printing: rubber stereotype, T86S86, No. 1
  - Phototypsetting, T91
    - Photographic negative, T91, No. 1
    - Fotosetter matrix, T91, No. 2
  - Second generation: linofilm: VIP, T92
    - Font grid: Eurostyle Bold Extended typeface, T92, No. 1
    - Font grid: Plantin typeface, T92, No. 2
- Music Engraving, V2
  The music engraving collection belonged to one of the last music engravers in the United States, Richard B. Pettit, who practiced his trade in Ojai, California, until his death in 1981. Glossy photographs in the collection show him at work in his studio, various tools in hand. There is also a plate engraved by him, with proof (white on green), and a final, printed page (black on white).
  In the early years of printing, music was often reproduced by means of woodblocks. Some printers used movable type, but setting music type is a process so complex that is was largely replaced during the 17th century by engraved plates. In the 18th century the introduction of punches reduced the amount of engraving; nevertheless, the combined process of punching and engraving was still called music engraving. It remained the chief means of reproducing music until the development of the music typewriter in the 20th century.
  The music engraver begins by cutting staff lines into a plate with a staff-scorer; then he measures off proper spacing for the composition he is copying; next he taps note-heads, sharps, flats, clefs, and other signs into the plate with a hammer and punches; he cuts stem, ties, and slurs with gravers of different kinds; he adds lyrics, titles, tempo markings, etc., with punches that contain letterforms. He always works form right to left, exactly the opposite was the finished, printed music will read. A skilled engraver may take as many as three hours to produce one plate, or one page, of music.
  Most of the punches in the collection were handmade of soft steel during the 19th century, a few during the 20th, in German, the center of the craft. Tool designations in the inventory of the collection are those of Oscar Herbert, the engraver’s mentor, friend, and co-worker for twenty-five years, who visited The Bancroft Library in 1981 to demonstrate the use of the equipment. The entire collection is the gift of Pettit’s daughters, Lisa Pettit and Elsie Pettit Wojnar of Champaign, Illinois.
  - Cutting tools, V22
    - Staff scorers, V22C32, No. 1-6
    - Staff scoring machine, V22C33
    - Machine heads, V22C334, No. 3-7 (No. 1-2 not received)
    - Gravers, V22G24, No. 1-17
    - Graver stand, V22G241
    - Hooks, V22H25, No. 1-6
    - Auxilliary tools, V22T26, No. 1-19
  - Punches, V23
    - Braces, V23B32, No. 1-17
    - Circles, V23C24, No. 1-20
    - Dynamic marks, V23C25, No. 2.1-5.9
    - Dynamic signs, V23D26, No. 1-11
    - Shaped notes, V23N34, No. 5bl-5w7
    - Note stems and dots, V23N35, No. 1-22
    - Numerals, V23N66, No. 10.1-20.9
    - Symbols: No. 3 size, long font, V23S33, No. 1-73
    - Symbols: No. 1 size, partial font, V23S34, No. 1-20
    - Symbols: various partial fonts, V23S38, No. 4.1-14.1
    - Slurs, V23T26, No. 1-21
    - Logotypes, V23W35, No. 10.1-17.4
    - Micellaneous, V23Z44, No. 1-12
  - Punches: alphabets, V24
    - Small octavo No. 7, V24A7, No. 1-73
    - Small italic No. 8, V24A8, No. 1-73
    - Medium italic No. 10, V24A10, No. 1-73
    - Text No. 11, V24A11, No. 1-73
    - Medium title No. 18, V24A18, No. 1-73
    - Large title No. 28, V24A28, No. 1-73
  - Additional equipment, V26
    - Proofing Roller, V26, No. 1
  - Supplies, V27
    - Ink, V27P24, No. 1-3
    - Metal plates, V27P26
  - Plates and proofs (samples of work), V28
    - Plate for page of organ music, V28, No. 1
    - Proof: white on green, V28, No. 2
    - Printed page: black on white, V28, No. 3
  - Illustrative photographs: Rich B. Pettit at work in his studio (Explanatory notes and biographical sketch laid in), V29
    - Using roller, BART V26 No. 1, to make a relief proof, V29, No. 1
    - Portrait of Richard Pettit, V29, No. 3
    - Using roller, BART V26 No. 1, to make relief proof, V29, No. 4
    - Punching into a plate, V29, No. 5
    - Using roller, BART V26 No. 1, to make a relief proof, V29, No. 6
    - Portrait of Richard Pettit, V29, No. 8
    - Portrait of Richard Pettit, V29, No. 9
    - Richard Pettit at work, surrounced by punches, BART V23 B32, gravers, BART V22G24, BART V22 G241, hooks, BART V22 M25, and scorers BART V22 C32, V29, No. 11
    - Final intaglio proof and plate, V29, No. 12
    - Richard Pettit punching an accent mark into a plate, V29, No. 13
    - Richard Pettit using a tie-graver fron assortment BART V22 G24 and BART V22 G241, V29, No. 14
    - Close-up of Richard Pettit using a tie graver, BART V22 G24, V29, No. 15
    - Richard Pettit at his rolling press (not given to Bancroft), V29, No. 16
    - Gravers, BART V22 G24, hoooks, BART V22 M25, and scorers BART V22 C32, in rack BART V22 G241, V29, No. 17
    - Richard Pettit adding a tie from relief proof, V29, No. 18
    - Richard Pettit pulling a relief proof from plate, V29, No. 19
    - Richard Pettit surrounded by punches, BART V23, at his lithographic-stone work bench, V29, No. 20
    - Richard Peti using staff scoring machine, V22 C334, V29, No. 21
- Map Printing, V3
  From the mid-19th century until well into the 20th, the leading map-making firms in the U.S. used a wax-engraving process sometimes called cerography. It consisted essentially in drawing or transferring an image on a plate covered with a wax composition in which letters and numerals could be engraved or stamped
  - [Miscellaneous Map Printing Tools], V3
    - Type-stamping stick, V3, No. 1
    - Map-printing kit, V3, No. 2
- Specialty Printing, W2
  Aside from the four-color process on tin (examples show color scales and register marks), the bulk of the collection consists of printing from the Panama-Pacific International Exposition: celluloid buttons and ribbons printed or foil stamped, bronzed ribbons and paper, metal pins, fobs, and lapel buttons. Usually these honored special visitors on special dasys, e.g. “Denmarks Dag” or “Siam P.P.I.E.,” although some were for winners in livestock and other competitions.
  - Tin: four-color process printing, W2S31
    - "MJB Coffee Regular:" four-color process printing, W23S31, No. 1
    - "MJB Coffee Automatic Drip:" four color process printing, W2S31, No. 2
    - "MJB Premium Flake Ground Coffee:" four-color process printing, W2S31, No. 3
  - Celluloid buttons (Panama Pacific International Exposition, 1915), W2S32
    - "Panama-Pacific International Exposition, San Francisco, California 1915, W2S32, No. 1
    - Matching cuff link, W2S32, No. 2
    - Matching cuff link, W2S32, No. 3
    - "Edison Day Oct. 21", W2S32, No. 4
    - "Memorial Duilding, G. Washington," verso "This button means a brick for the George Washing Memorial Hall", W2S32, No. 5
    - "Apple annual Pajaro Valley 1910, Oct. 10-15, Walsonville, Cal.", W2S32, No. 6
    - "Panama-California Exposition San Diego 1915", W2S32, No. 7
    - "Spokane Day, P.P.I.E. May 25, 1915, W2S32, No. 8
    - Italian emblem, W2S32, No. 9
    - "Danmarks Dag P.P.I.E., 5 Juni 1915", W2S32, No. 10
    - "Gem of the Mountains", W2S32, No. 11
    - "The Netherlands Building of P.P.I.E. 1915", W2S32, No. 12
    - "Ua Mau Ke Ea O Ka Aina I Ka Pono Aloha", W2S32, No. 13
    - "Los Angeles County Day Panama-Pacific Internation Exposition April 15, 1915", W2S32, No. 14
    - "Judge", W2S32, No. 15
    - "San Francisco '1915' Modesto Butter 'All-the-time'", W2S32, No. 16
    - "Mississippi Day P.P.I.E. Sept 4, 1915", W2S32, No. 17
    - "P.P.I.E. 'See America First' Great Northern Railway Glacier National Park 1915", W2S32, No. 18
    - "Pacific Gas and Electric Company Pacific Courteous Continuous Service, W2S32, No. 19
    - "Panama-Pacific International Exposition, Admit One, Opening Day, Feb. 20, 1915, Charles C. Moore, President", W2S32, No. 20
    - "How'dy Pap, San Francisco, Cal., Loyal Order of the Moose, Moose Day P.P.I.E. July 25, 1915", W2S32, No. 21
    - "Denmark Building", W2S32, No. 22
    - 4th July Official Committee 1915", W2S32, No. 23
    - "Official Souvenir", W2S32, No. 24
    - "Panama-Pacific International Exposition, San Francisco, California, 1915", W2S32, No. 25
    - "Panama-Pacific International Exposition, San Francisco, California, 1915", W2S32, No. 26
    - "Philadelphia 1776 San Francisco 1915", W2S32, No. 27
    - "Oro y plata", W2S32, No. 28
    - "P.P.I.E., April 5, 1915, Siskiyou, The Head of California", W2S32, No. 29
  - Cloth ribbons (Panama Pacific International Exposition, 1915), W2S34
    - "Notice" [to miners], W2S34, No. 1
    - "Butte County, March 31, 1915", W2S34, No. 2
    - "Calaveras County, P.P.I.E. 1915", W2S34, No. 3
    - "California Orange Day Citrus Protective League, March 20, 1915", W2S34, No. 4
    - "California Ripe Olive Day Committee Butte County Division March 31, 1915", W2S34, No. 5
    - Southern Pacific, San Francisco, March 10, 1915, Panama-Pacific Internation Exposition", W2S34, No. 6
    - "Glenn County, Why?, Irrigation, P.P.I.E., March 30, 1915", W2S34, No. 7
    - "Idaho", W2S34, No. 8
    - "Santa Cruz County Day, P.P.I.E., San Francisco, March 2, 1915", W2S34, No. 9
    - "Dedication Day, April 3, 1915, Press Club of San Francisco, P.P.I.E. 1915", W2S34, No. 10
    - "The Living Flag of the Grand Army of the Republic for the 1915 International Exposition of San Francisco", W2S34, No. 11
    - "Massachusetts July 19, 1915 P.P.I.E.", W2S34, No. 12
    - "Meet Us Here Again October First Modoc County April 7, 15", W2S34, No. 13
    - "Missouri Day Panama-Pacific International Exposition May 3, 1915", W2S34, No. 14
    - "1915 American Press Humorists 13th Annual Convention P.P.I.E. San Francisco", W2S34, No. 15
    - "Offficial Badge Modoc County Day P.P.I.E. April 7", W2S34, No. 16
    - "New England Association, Massachusets, San Francisco", W2S34, No. 17
    - Women's Pacific Coast Good Roads Association Convention, P.P.I.E. May 6-7-8 1915", W2S34, No. 18
    - "Non-smokers' Protective League of America San Francisco, Cal. 1915", W2S34, No. 19
    - "Vanderbilt Grand Prix", W2S34, No. 20
    - "Panama-Pacific International Exposition, Monterey County", W2S34, No. 21
    - "Placer The Gateway County Reception Committee", W2S34, No. 22
    - Panama-Pacific International Exposition Reception Committee, Insurance Day, April 18th, 1914", W2S34, No. 23
    - "San Francisco Day, San Francisco Commerical Club, Tuesday, April 18th, 1916", W2S34, No. 24
    - "S.F. Real Estate Board Day P.P.I.E., March 27, 1915", W2S34, No. 25
    - "San Francisco Retail Bakers Association P.P.I.E. June 9th 1915", W2S34, No. 26
    - "China Day P.P.I.E. Sept. 23 1915", W2S34, No. 27
    - "Sonoma County Day 1915", W2S34, No. 28
    - "P.P.I.E. 1915 'Year Before Opening' Celebration Committee 1914", W2S34, No. 29
    - "Panama-Pacific Internation Exposition, Transportation Club of San Francisco", W2S34, No. 30
    - "Panama-Pacific International Exposition, Southern California Editorial Asssociation, December 4-5-6 1913", W2S34, No. 31
    - "Panama-Pacific International Exposition, Yolo County, California", W2S34, No. 32
    - "Dedication, Tuolumne County, April 14, 1915 P.P.I.E. San Francisco, Cal., W2S34, No. 33
    - "Contra Cost County Day April 3, 1915, Agricultural and Industrial Center P.P.I.E.", W2S34, No. 34
    - "Vallejo", W2S34, No. 35
    - "Wells Fargo Day June 15th, 1915 Wells Fargo & Co. Express Panama Pacific International Exposition", W2S34, No. 36
    - "United Artisans 1915 Convention Panama-Pacific Fair", W2S34, No. 37
    - "Dedication Indiana Building P.P.I.E. Hon. Chas. Fairbanks Presiding, March 8, 1915", W2S34, No. 38
    - "Flying Legion San Francisco 1915", W2S34, No. 39
    - "Dedication Day Republic of Guatemala March 15 1915", W2S34, No. 40
    - "Amador", W2S34, No. 41
  - Foil stamping on cloth ribbon (Panama Pacific International Exposition, 1915), W2S351
    - "The Business Men's League of St. Louis", W28351, No. 1
    - "Nevada Day July 7 B.P.O.E. Nevada T.P.A.", W28351, No. 2
    - "Chicago Day July 27th", W28351, No. 3
    - "From Phila., Pa. to San Francisco, Cal. 1915", W28351, No. 4
    - "Guest Sixth Annual Convention I.A.R.C. July 1915", W28351, No. 5
    - "Guest", W28351, No. 6
    - "Grand Council of California U.C.T.", W28351, No. 7
    - "New Jersey Commission P.P.I.E. 1915", W28351, No. 8
    - "Portola Day Oct. 23, 1915", W28351, No. 9
    - "San Francisco, The Pacific Telephone and Telegraph Co., New York, January 25, 1915", W28351, No. 10
    - "Ireland's Day at P.P.I.E., March 17, 1915, San Francisco", W28351, No. 11
    - "Solano County 1915", W28351, No. 12
    - "Panama-Pacific International Exposition San Francisco 1915...Dorset Fat Pen", W28351, No. 13
    - "Duroc-Jersey Boar Eighteen and under Twenty Four Months", W28351, No. 14
    - "Hampshire Fat Wether Champion, Any Age", W28351, No. 15
    - "Morgan Stallion Reserve Grand Champion, Any Age", W28351, No. 16
    - "Morgan Stallion Senior Champion Three Years Old and over", W28351, No. 17
    - "Oxford Fat Pen", W28351, No. 18
    - "Poland-China Herd Boar and Three Sows over One Year", W28351, No. 19
    - "Southdown Ram One Year and under Two", W28351, No. 20
    - "Standard Trotter Filly Foal", W28351, No. 21
    - "Standard Trotter Filly Foal", W28351, No. 22
    - "Large Yorkshire Get of Sire Four Animals", W28351, No. 23
    - "Large Yorkshire Get of Sire Four Animals", W28351, No. 24
    - "International Grand Prix Race, President Exposition, February 27, 10 A.M. 1915", W28351, No. 25
    - "Floor P.P.I.E. 1915", W28351, No. 26
    - "Vanderbilt Cup Race, President Exposition, February 22, 10 A.M. 1915", W28351, No. 27
  - Bronzing on cloth (Panama-Pacific International Exposition, 1915), W2S352
    - "Examiner Day Committee", W2S352, No. 1
    - "Committee Ireland's Day P.P.I.E. March 17, 1915", W2S352, No. 2
    - "New Yorkers", W2S352, No. 3
    - "1915 Panama Pacific Internation Exposition Indiana Building Site Dedicated Oct. 23, 1912 San Francisco", W2S352, No. 4
    - "San Joaquin County", W2S352, No. 5
    - "Tracy", W2S352, No. 6
  - Bronzing on paper (Panama Pacific International Exposition, 1915), W2S353
    - "Pioneer and Old Settler's Day 'The Days of Old, the Days of Gold, the Days of '49' Oct. 16, 1915 Panama Pacific Exposition", W2S353, No. 1
    - "Pioneer and Old Settler's Day 'The Days of Old, the Days of Gold, the Days of '49' Oct. 16, 1915 Panama Pacific Exposition" (Same as No. 1), W2S353, No. 2
  - Metal pins, watch fobs, lapel buttons, reated objects (Panama Pacific International Exposition, 1915) and other items, W2S36
    - Metal enamel pin:"Siam P.P.I.E.", W2S36, No. 1
    - Metal enamel pin: "Idaho Panama-Pacific International Exposition San Francisco 1915", W2S36, No. 2
    - Medal: "Panama-Pacific International Exposition Commission", W2S36, No. 3
    - Medal "Maryland at Panama Pacific International Exposition 1915", W2S36, No. 4
    - Medal: "West Virginia", W2S36, No. 5
    - Medal: "Deutsch Amerikanisher Nat'l Bund August 2-8-1915", W2S36, No. 6
    - Pendant in shape of Liberty Bell: "Philadelphia 1915 San Francisco", W2S36, No. 7
    - Watch fob: "California State Legislator's Day H.I.J.M's Commission P.P.I.E. March 20 1915", W2S36, No. 8